<div>
	<p>Before using this website and the database, and before making data available to you, you have to read this agreement carefully, understand it and accept the terms and conditions set forth herein.</p>
	<h1>Terms of Use and Data Protection Agreement</h1>
	<h2>§ 1 Subject of the Agreement</h2>
	<p>1.1	The Conference on Jewish Material Claims against Germany, Inc., with its headquarter at 1359 Broadway, Suite 2000, New York, NY 10018, USA (“Claims Conference”), allocates funds to grantee organizations and institutions around the world that provide essential social services for Jewish victims of Nazi persecution (“Agency” or “Agencies”). Each Agency is relied on by the Claims Conference to be familiar with the priorities in their service areas and how to address them.  The Claims Conference works closely with each Agency, to assure that Jewish victims of Nazi persecution remain cared-for, fed, receive care in their homes, are able to have access to socialization opportunities, and are supported in applying for government benefits to which they may be entitled.</p>
	<p>1.2	The Subject of this Terms of Use and Data Protection Agreement (“Agreement”) is the exchange of Personal Data between the Claims Conference and the Agency, as well as Processing Personal Data in accordance with EU Data Protection Laws.  The currently applicable legal data protection regulations are to be observed, in particular those of the Directive 95/46/EC of the European Parliament and of the Council (hereinafter: Directive 95/46/EC).</p>
	<h2>§ 2 Definitions as used in this Agreement</h2>
	<p>2.1	“Personal Data” shall mean any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person (“Data Subject”); an identifiable person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identification number or to one or more actors specific to her/his physical, physiological, mental, economic, cultural or social identity.</p>
	<p>2.2	“Sensitive Personal Data” means Personal Data consisting of information as to - (a) the racial or ethnic origin of the Data Subject, (b) her/his political opinions, (c ) her/his religious beliefs or other beliefs of a similar nature, (d) whether she/he is a member of a trade union, (e) her/his physical or mental health or condition, (f) her/his sexual life, (g) the commission or alleged commission by her/him of any offence, or (h) any proceedings for any offence committed or alleged to have been committed by her/him, the disposal of such proceedings or the sentence of any court in such proceedings.</p>
	<p>2.3	“Processing” of Personal Data shall mean any operation or set of operations which is performed upon Personal Data, whether or not by automatic means, such as collection, recording, organization, storage, adaptation or alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure by transmission, dissemination or otherwise making available, alignment or combination, blocking, erasure or destruction.</p>
	<p>2.4	“Personal Data Filing System” or “Filing System” shall mean any structured set of Personal Data which are accessible according to specific criteria, whether centralized, decentralized or dispersed on a functional or geographical basis.</p>
	<p>2.5	“Controller” shall mean the natural or legal person, public authority, agency or any other body which alone or jointly with others determines the purposes and means of the Processing of Personal Data; where the purposes and means of processing are determined by EU-Member State or EU-Community laws or regulations, the controller or the specific criteria for her/his nomination may be designated by national Member State or EU-Community law.</p>
	<p>2.6	“Processor” shall mean a natural or legal person, public authority, agency or any other body which processes Personal Data on behalf of the Controller.</p>
	<p>2.7	“Third Party” shall mean any natural or legal person, public authority, agency or any other body other than the Data Subject, the Controller, the Processor and the persons who, under the direct authority of the Controller or the Processor, are authorized to Process the data.</p>
	<p>2.8	“Recipient” shall mean a natural or legal person, public authority, agency or any other body to whom data are disclosed, whether a third party or not; however, authorities which may receive data in the framework of a particular inquiry shall not be regarded as recipients.</p>
	<p>2.9	“The Data Subject's Consent” shall mean any freely given specific and informed indication of her/his wishes by which the data subject signifies her/his agreement to personal data relating to her/him being processed.</p>
	<h2>§ 3 Purpose of transmission of data</h2>
	<p>3.1	The Claims Conference, as the Controller, runs and maintains certain databases with Personal Data concerning individual clients and applicants, who are being served by Agencies under the supervision of the Claims Conference, as described in section 1.1.</p>
	<p>3.2	In order to coordinate and monitor these services, the Claims Conference is in close contact with the Agencies, to keep Holocaust victims healthy and fed, to deliver care in their homes, to bring them socialization opportunities, to obtain any government benefits to which they may be entitled.</p>
	<p>3.3	The purpose of this agreement is to govern the use of the website and the database, as well as Processing and transmitting of Personal Data between the Claims Conference and the Agencies, to manage, coordinate, supervise and to pay for the services provided to individuals by the Agency/Agencies.</p>
	<p>3.4	The Agency is not granted any further rights to use the Personal Data other than for the above defined and agreed purpose.</p>
	<h2>§ 4 Procedure</h2>
	<p>The procedure agreed between the Claims Conference and the Agency will be carried out in the following steps: </p>
	<p>4.1	Every person who, under the direct authority of the Agency is authorized to Process Personal Data on behalf of the Agency though the website interface, will receive individual log in data from the Claims Conference such as a username and password.</p>
	<p>4.2	Every person Processing Personal Data on behalf of the Agency is restricted by the system to access only such Personal Data of those individuals the Agency is taking care of. The Agency and the persons acting on behalf of the Agency will not have access to any other Personal Data in that database, concerning individual clients the Agency is not taking care of. </p>
	<p>4.3	Every person shall only Process accurate and up-to-date Personal Data and information regarding support and services carried out by the Agency and the Agency’s staff. Every person Processing Data shall take reasonable steps to ensure the accuracy of any Personal Data, and, if necessary, shall update and correct the information accordingly.</p>
	<p>4.4	Information and Personal Data concerning the services provided by the Agency will be submitted and Processed in a secure environment and stored in a secure database of the Claims Conference.</p>
	<h2>§ 5 Confidentiality and Admission</h2>
	<p>5.1	No employee, manager, director or any other person of the Agency shall Process or use Personal Data without authorization of the Claims Conference. </p>
	<p>5.2	The individual username and password are to be kept secret and under no circumstances is it permissible to share a username and password. </p>
	<p>5.3	On taking up their duties, any person Processing Data on behalf of the Agency through this website shall be required to agree in writing to this Agreement and to maintain such confidentiality by accepting the terms and conditions set forth herein (Admission).</p>
	<p>5.4	This Agreement shall continue to be valid after termination of their activity.</p>
	<h2>§ 6 Rights and Obligations of the Claims Conference</h2>
	<p>6.1	The Claims Conference will observe the necessary technical and organizational security measures.  Where Personal Data and Sensitive Personal Data are processed or used automatically, the internal organization of Claims Conference is to be arranged in such a way that it meets the specific requirements of EU data protection laws.  In particular, measures suited to the type of Personal Data or data categories to be protected shall be taken,</p>
	<ul>
		<li>to prevent unauthorized persons from gaining access to Personal Data Filing Systems with which Personal Data are processed or used (physical data access control),</li>
		<li>to prevent Personal Data Filing Systems from being used without authorization (logical data access control),</li>
		<li>to ensure that persons entitled to use a Personal Data Filing Systems have access only to the data to which they have a right of access, and that Personal Data cannot be read, copied, modified or removed without authorization in the course of Processing or use and after storage (data access control),</li>
		<li>to ensure that Personal Data cannot be read, copied, modified or removed without authorization during electronic transmission or transport, and that it is possible to check and establish to which bodies the transfer of Personal Data by means of data transmission facilities is envisaged (data transmission control),</li>
		<li>to ensure that it is possible to check and establish whether and by whom Personal Data have been input into Personal Data Filing Systems, modified or removed (data input control),</li>
		<li>to ensure that, in the case of commissioned Processing of Personal Data, the data are processed strictly in accordance with the instructions of the principal (data job control),</li>
		<li>to ensure that Personal Data are protected from accidental destruction or loss (data availability control),</li>
		<li>to ensure that data collected for different purposes can be processed separately (data purpose control).</li>
	</ul>
	<p>6.2	The data processing will be carried out by using data processing equipment for which technical and organizational measures have been taken to protect Personal Data, including using adequate and up-to-date virus and spyware protection.</p>
	<p>6.3	The server rooms and the anterooms are locked when nobody is in the rooms. </p>
	<p>6.4	It is only possible to access a Claims Conference staff-PC, any other PC used to Process Personal Data as well as the Claims Conference database with a secure password. These passwords must be changed every 90 days and are regulated by the system.</p>
	<p>6.5	The Claims Conference and the Agency are separately responsible for conforming with such statutory data protection regulations as are applicable to them.</p>
	<p>6.6	The Claims Conference shall inform the Agency without undue delay and comprehensively about any errors or irregularities related to statutory provisions on the Processing of Personal Data detected during a verification of the results of such Processing.</p>
	<h2>§ 7 Rights and Obligations of the Agency</h2>
	<p>7.1	The Agency is responsible for safeguarding the rights of the individuals concerned. The Agency will observe the necessary technical and organizational security measures. This means, where Personal Data and Sensitive Personal Data are Processed or used automatically, the internal organization of Agency is to be arranged in such a way that it meets the specific requirements of EU data protection laws.  In particular, measures suited to the type of Personal Data or data categories to be protected shall be taken,</p>
	<p>to prevent unauthorized persons from gaining access to Personal Data Filing Systems with which Personal Data are processed or used (physical data access control),</p>
	<p>to prevent Personal Data Filing Systems from being used without authorization (logical data access control),</p>
	<p>to ensure that persons entitled to use a Personal Data Filing Systems have access only to the data to which they have a right of access, and that Personal Data cannot be read, copied, modified or removed without authorization in the course of Processing or use and after storage (data access control),</p>
	<p>to ensure that Personal Data cannot be read, copied, modified or removed without authorization during electronic transmission or transport, and that it is possible to check and establish to which bodies the transfer of Personal Data by means of data transmission facilities is envisaged (data transmission control),</p>
	<p>to ensure that it is possible to check and establish whether and by whom Personal Data have been input into Personal Data Filing Systems, modified or removed (data input control),</p>
	<p>to ensure that, in the case of commissioned Processing of Personal Data, the data are processed strictly in accordance with the instructions of the principal (data job control),</p>
	<p>to ensure that Personal Data are protected from accidental destruction or loss (data availability control),</p>
	<p>to ensure that data collected for different purposes can be processed separately (data purpose control).</p>
	<p>7.2	The data processing will be carried out by using data processing equipment for which technical and organizational measures have been taken to protect Personal Data, including using adequate and up-to-date virus and spyware protection.</p>
	<p>7.3	It is only possible to access a staff-PC of the Agency, any other PC used to Process Personal Data as well as the database with a secure password. These passwords must be changed every 90 days and are regulated by the system.</p>
	<p>7.4	The Agency shall inform the Claims Conference without undue delay and comprehensively about any errors or irregularities related to statutory provisions on the Processing of Personal Data detected during a verification of the results of such Processing.</p>
	<p>7.5	The Agency confirms that it is aware of the relevant data protection provisions and guarantees that it provably previously acquaints the staff carrying out the work with the decisive regulations of data protection law and in particular with data secrecy in accordance with Directive 95/46/EC. </p>
	<p>7.6	The Agency as Processor shall collect, process and use Personal Data only within the scope of Claims Conference’s instructions.</p>
	<p>7.7	Upon Claims Conference’s request, the Agency shall provide a comprehensive and current Personal Data protection and security programme covering data Processing hereunder.</p>
	<p>7.8	The Agency shall ensure that any personnel entrusted with Processing Personal Data have undertaken to comply with the principle of data secrecy and have been duly instructed on the relevant aspects. The secrecy-obligation shall continue after the termination of the Agreement.</p>
	<p>7.9	The Agency shall be obliged to audit and verify the fulfilment of the above-entitled obligations and shall maintain an adequate documentation of such verification.</p>
	<h2>§ 8 Audit Obligations</h2>
	<p>8.1	The Claims Conference shall, prior to the commencement of processing, and in regular intervals thereafter, audit the technical and organizational measures taken by the Agency, and shall document the resulting findings.  For such purpose, Claims Conference may collect voluntary disclosures from the Agency. </p>
	<p>8.2	The Agency shall, upon Claims Conference’s written request and within a reasonable period of time, provide the Claims Conference with all information necessary for such audit.</p>
	<h2>§ 9 Subcontractors</h2>
	<p>The Agency shall be entitled to subcontract Processor’s obligations to third parties only with Claims Conference’s written consent.</p>
	<h2>§ 10 Liability</h2>
	<p>10.1	The Claims Conference, the Agency and every person bound by this Agreement shall fully comply with this Agreement.  </p>
	<p>10.2	Failure to follow these obligations hereunder may result in employee corrective action, including termination and other penalties as provided by law. </p>
	<p>10.3	The Agency and every person bound by this Agreement may be liable in case of a breach of this Agreement.  Applicants, clients, Data Subjects, the Claims Conference and others, may have the right to claim enforcement of this Agreement, and to receive compensation and damages in case of noncompliance with this Agreement, and compensation in case of a misuse of their Personal Data.</p>
	<p>10.4	This website, the database and all of the functions provided by Claims Conference are provided “as is” and “as available”, and the Claims Conference reserves the right to change the content, the style and the technology of the website, the database and any other function at any time at its sole discretion.</p>
	<p>10.5	The Claims Conference shall not be liable for damages resulting directly or indirectly from the use of the website and the use of the information contained therein, in particular for the loss, delay, delay, alteration, manipulation and/or misdirection of data during data entry, capture, transmission and/or storage, which are caused by external data networks, third-party phone lines and/or other hardware and/or software of the user.</p>
	<h2>§ 11 Duration and Replacement of this Agreement</h2>
	<p>11.1	This Agreement will be kept under regular review of the Claims Conference and may be subject to changes at any time.</p>
	<p>11.2	It is envisaged by the Claims Conference to implement Binding Corporate Rules as defined by EU Data Protection Law in the near future.  This Agreement shall be valid until terminated, changed or replaced by the Binding Corporate Rules of the Claims Conference. When available, the Agency shall agree to the Binding Corporate Rules, which shall replace this agreement as soon as the Binding Corporate Rules are available and approved by the EU data protection authorities.</p>
	<p>Declaration of Admission</p>
	<p>My name is _________________, working with and on behalf of the Agency ____________________. </p>
	<p>I have read and understood the terms and conditions of this Agreement. I agree and accept.</p>
	<p>YES 	[   ]	NO 	[   ]</p>
	<p>I am the CEO/Managing Director of the Agency and I have the power to legally bind the Agency. I have read and understood the terms and conditions of this Agreement. I agree and accept in representation and on behalf of the Agency.</p>
	<p>YES 	[   ]	NO 	[   ]</p>
	<p>After accepting this Agreement, a downloadable version is available on our website.  </p>
	<p>[Version 1.1 - April 2013]</p>
	<p></p>
</div>